<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate</id>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
    <name>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate</name>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate.desktop</launchable>
    <update_contact>idea@jetbrains.com</update_contact>
    <summary>Leading Java and Kotlin IDE</summary>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issues/IDEA/</url>
    <url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/documentation/</url>
    <url type="homepage">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/</url>
    <developer id="com.jetbrains">
        <name>JetBrains s.r.o.</name>
    </developer>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="social-info">moderate</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>
    <branding>
        <color scheme_preference="light" type="primary">#f4f4f4</color>
        <color scheme_preference="dark" type="primary">#9d4f94</color>
    </branding>
    <categories>
        <category>Development</category>
        <category>IDE</category>
    </categories>
    <keywords>
        <keyword>kotlin</keyword>
        <keyword>java</keyword>
        <keyword>development</keyword>
        <keyword>ide</keyword>
    </keywords>
    <requires>
        <memory>2048</memory>
        <control>keyboard</control>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
    </requires>
    <recommends>
        <memory>8192</memory>
        <display_length compare="ge">1080</display_length>
        <internet>always</internet>
    </recommends>
    <supports>
        <internet>offline-only</internet>
    </supports>
    <description>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is a full-featured Java and Kotlin IDE that provides everything you need out of the box, including built-in developer tools such as database tools and profilers, web and enterprise frameworks, remote development, and much more.</p>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is available for a free 30-day evaluation. Monthly and yearly subscription options are available for companies and individual users.</p>
        <p>NOTE: This wrapper is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by JetBrains s.r.o.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/img/overview-heading-screenshot.png</image>
            <caption>Overview heading</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-1.png</image>
            <caption>Java support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-2.png</image>
            <caption>Kotlin support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/full-line-code-completion.png</image>
            <caption>Full line code completion</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2023/AI_Assistant_features_v2.png</image>
            <caption>AI Assistant</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2021/LanguageInjections.png</image>
            <caption>Language injections</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2021/IntelligentCodeCompletion.png</image>
            <caption>Intelligent code completion</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2023/ProblemsToolsWindow.png</image>
            <caption>The Problems tool window</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2023/InspectionsAndContextActions.png</image>
            <caption>Inspections and context actions</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2021/LiveTemplates.png</image>
            <caption>Live templates</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2021/ProjectWideRefactoring.png</image>
            <caption>Project-wide refactoring</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/screenshots/features_2023/CodeDuplicates.png</image>
            <caption>Detection of code duplicates</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="2024.3.1" date="2024-12-09">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/</url>
            <description>
                <p>This version introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows you to find and fix security vulnerabilities in real time, ensuring your code is not only more efficient but also more secure – simply install the Security Analysis by Qodana plugin.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>JSON schema validation is now aware of YAML tags, for example, !reference in a .gitlab-ci.yml file.</li>
                    <li>When changing the Version Control setting for remote development environments, the Open Diff as Editor Tab checkbox now works as intended.</li>
                    <li>The Render documentation comments option again works as expected.</li>
                    <li>Settings sync again works with self-signed certificates when a proxy is used.</li>
                    <li>Debugging a web application deployed on WebLogic 12.2 no longer affects IDE performance.</li>
                    <li>The IDE once again correctly matches Maven config files when working with several Maven projects simultaneously within one IDEA project.</li>
                    <li>Scroll positions are once again in sync for split panes of the same file, when the “Open in Opposite Group” and “Split…” actions are used.</li>
                    <li>The Merge Request Diff view again correctly shows the selected file.</li>
                    <li>The conversion to an enhanced switch now retains the default value.</li>
                    <li>We fixed the issue where, in some cases, Inline Method refactoring created unnecessary intermediate variables.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2024.3" date="2024-11-12">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3/</url>
            <description>
                <p>Key highlights include a visual representation of your code’s logical structure in the Structure tool window, a smoother debugging experience for Kubernetes applications, and cluster-wide Kubernetes log access. This version also moves K2 mode out of Beta.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The Structure tool window now includes a Logical code structure alongside the familiar Physical structure. This allows you to view not only classes, methods, and fields but also the links and interactions between components in your project.</li>
                    <li>We’ve made debugging Kubernetes applications even easier. You can use the Add Tunnel for Remote Debug option to make your workstation a virtual part of the Kubernetes cluster, allowing you to swap in a pod and debug microservices locally with your preferred tools.</li>
                    <li>IntelliJ IDEA now offers cluster-wide Kubernetes log access with streaming and pattern matching. This feature provides a centralized view of all events across pods, nodes, and services, helping you quickly identify issues without manually checking each log.</li>
                    <li>K2 mode has officially moved out of Beta and is now Stable and ready for general use.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2024.2" date="2024-08-07">
            <url type="details">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/2024-2/</url>
            <description>
                <p>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Ultimate lets you run Spring Data JPA methods directly in the IDE for instant repository query verification. It also simplifies the management of cron expressions by providing inline descriptions and advanced autocompletion, and it upgrades the HTTP Client to use the GraalJS execution engine. Additionally, this version enhances IntelliJ IDEA’s overall startup efficiency by enabling key functionalities during project indexing, and it integrates K2 mode, now in Beta, to further boost the IDE’s performance and stability for Kotlin, as well as its support for language features.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2024.1" date="2024-04-04">
            <url type="details">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/2024-1/</url>
            <description>
                <p>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1 introduces an array of exciting upgrades to help streamline your workflows. IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate now boasts full line code completion, providing comprehensive code-aware suggestions for entire lines of code. Support for Java 22 ensures compatibility with the latest language features. The overhauled terminal enhances command-line operations, while sticky lines in the editor facilitate smoother navigation through codebases.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2023.3" date="2023-12-06">
            <url type="details">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/2023-3/</url>
            <description>
                <p>The IntelliJ IDEA 2023.3 release signifies the continued evolution of AI Assistant, which has now moved beyond the technical preview stage and features a host of exciting improvements. In other areas, this version includes comprehensive support for the latest Java 21 features, introduces an intuitive floating toolbar with editing actions, and adds a Run to Cursor inlay option for an enhanced debugging workflow. IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate now provides a seamless out-of-the-box Kubernetes development experience.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
</component>
