<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate</id>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
    <name>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate</name>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate.desktop</launchable>
    <update_contact>idea@jetbrains.com</update_contact>
    <summary>Leading Java and Kotlin editor</summary>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issues/IDEA/</url>
    <url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea</url>
    <url type="homepage">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/</url>
    <url type="contact">https://www.jetbrains.com/company/contacts</url>
    <developer id="com.jetbrains">
        <name>JetBrains s.r.o.</name>
    </developer>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="social-info">moderate</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>
    <branding>
        <color scheme_preference="light" type="primary">#ff8100</color>
        <color scheme_preference="dark" type="primary">#047dfc</color>
    </branding>
    <categories>
        <category>Development</category>
        <category>IDE</category>
    </categories>
    <keywords>
        <keyword>kotlin</keyword>
        <keyword>java</keyword>
        <keyword>development</keyword>
        <keyword>ide</keyword>
    </keywords>
    <requires>
        <memory>2048</memory>
        <control>keyboard</control>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
    </requires>
    <recommends>
        <memory>8192</memory>
        <display_length compare="ge">1080</display_length>
        <internet>always</internet>
    </recommends>
    <supports>
        <internet>offline-only</internet>
    </supports>
    <description>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA is an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for professional development in Java and Kotlin. It is designed to maximize developer productivity and has a strong focus on privacy and security. It does the routine and repetitive tasks for you by providing clever code completion, static code analysis, and refactorings. It lets you focus on the bright side of software development, making it not only productive but also an enjoyable experience.</p>
        <p>The development of modern applications involves using multiple languages, tools, frameworks, and technologies. IntelliJ IDEA is designed as an IDE for JVM languages, but numerous plugins can extend it to provide a polyglot experience.</p>
        <p>Use IntelliJ IDEA to develop applications in the following languages that can be compiled into the JVM bytecode, namely: Java, Kotlin, Scala and Groovy</p>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is a full-featured Java and Kotlin IDE. It includes all the features of the Community edition, plus adds support for languages that other IntelliJ platform-based IDEs focus on. It provides support for a variety of server-side and front-end frameworks, application servers, integration with database and profiling tools, and more.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-1.png</image>
            <caption>Java support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-2.png</image>
            <caption>Kotlin support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/AI_Assistant_features_v2.png</image>
            <caption>AI Assistant</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/ProblemsToolsWindow.png</image>
            <caption>The Problems tool window</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/CodeDuplicates.png</image>
            <caption>Detection of code duplicates</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="2025.3" date="2025-12-08">
            <description></description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.2.5" date="2025-11-20">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-5/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The IDE now correctly processes API calls when the Docker Engine is updated to v29.</li>
                    <li>Gradle 9.x projects with a Spring Boot now run as expected using the Gradle Runner.</li>
                    <li>Resolved an issue where the IDE could hang when scanning HTTP request files containing certain JSON structures.</li>
                    <li>The GitLab plugin now correctly handles large pipeline IDs.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.2.4" date="2025-10-23">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-4/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The uninstaller now works as expected and should no longer fail and report an error when uninstalling a patched version.</li>
                    <li>The IDE no longer freezes during code completion, which was previously caused by recursive StubIndex calls leading to a deadlock.</li>
                    <li>cURL command conversion in the HTTP Client no longer fails when using the -b or --cookie options.</li>
                    <li>The IDE now preserves original line endings when shelving and unshelving changes, instead of converting between CRLF and LF formats.</li>
                    <li>Background images are now correctly displayed in all tool windows.</li>
                    <li>Maven console output in Chinese is now displayed correctly.</li>
                    <li>In the AI diff view, the middle section with gutters has been resized for improved usability.</li>
                    <li>The IDE once again correctly builds dependent modules after the modules they are dependent on.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.2.3" date="2025-10-02">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-3/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Jira Task Server integration now works as before when fetching tasks.</li>
                    <li>Breakpoints now work as expected in the Services view when the ClassicUI plugin is enabled.</li>
                    <li>Opening multiple files at once is again accessible from the Find Usages dialog.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.2.2" date="2025-09-19">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-2/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The Run Maven Build icon is once again available in the Maven panel toolbar.</li>
                    <li>Remote SSH external tools now work as expected.</li>
                    <li>The IDE again correctly parses environment variables with semicolon values pasted in the Run/Debug dialog.</li>
                    <li>The IDE now properly handles MAVEN_OPTS environment variables.</li>
                    <li>On Windows, the Find in Files dialog again works as expected, closes correctly, and no longer shows a persistent green area.</li>
                    <li>Several issues with the terminal and WSL have been fixed.</li>
                    <li>The terminal now starts correctly and works as expected on Windows 10.</li>
                    <li>It is once again possible to switch between split editors using the Switch popup.</li>
                    <li>The distributionUrl for Gradle 9 now contains the proper version when creating a new project, preventing sync failures.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.2.1" date="2025-08-29">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-1/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The IDE correctly interprets and manages EAR artifact configurations as expected.</li>
                    <li>The Create Branch action is now accessible from all parts of the UI again.</li>
                    <li>Exporting diagrams as SVG now works as intended.</li>
                    <li>Maven Runner now properly recognizes and handles JVM options starting with the -X prefix in the VM Options field as expected.</li>
                    <li>Terminal processes again terminate correctly on Windows.</li>
                    <li>The IDE again correctly recognizes valid WebLogic server home paths and runs the WebLogic server.</li>
                    <li>The IDE now correctly runs the main() functions in Kotlin projects built with Gradle 9.0.</li>
                    <li>Maven run configurations again properly recognize and execute custom POM files specified with the -f option.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
</component>
