<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate</id>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
    <name>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate</name>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate.desktop</launchable>
    <update_contact>idea@jetbrains.com</update_contact>
    <summary>Leading Java and Kotlin editor</summary>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issues/IDEA/</url>
    <url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/documentation/</url>
    <url type="homepage">https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/</url>
    <url type="contact">https://www.jetbrains.com/company/contacts</url>
    <developer id="com.jetbrains">
        <name>JetBrains s.r.o.</name>
    </developer>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="social-info">moderate</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>
    <branding>
        <color scheme_preference="light" type="primary">#f4f4f4</color>
        <color scheme_preference="dark" type="primary">#9d4f94</color>
    </branding>
    <categories>
        <category>Development</category>
        <category>IDE</category>
    </categories>
    <keywords>
        <keyword>kotlin</keyword>
        <keyword>java</keyword>
        <keyword>development</keyword>
        <keyword>ide</keyword>
    </keywords>
    <requires>
        <memory>2048</memory>
        <control>keyboard</control>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
    </requires>
    <recommends>
        <memory>8192</memory>
        <display_length compare="ge">1080</display_length>
        <internet>always</internet>
    </recommends>
    <supports>
        <internet>offline-only</internet>
    </supports>
    <description>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is a full-featured Java and Kotlin IDE that provides everything you need out of the box, including built-in developer tools such as database tools and profilers, web and enterprise frameworks, remote development, and much more.</p>
        <p>IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is available for a free 30-day evaluation. Monthly and yearly subscription options are available for companies and individual users.</p>
        <p>NOTE: This wrapper is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by JetBrains s.r.o.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-1.png</image>
            <caption>Java support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/java-and-kotlin-support-2.png</image>
            <caption>Kotlin support</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/AI_Assistant_features_v2.png</image>
            <caption>AI Assistant</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/ProblemsToolsWindow.png</image>
            <caption>The Problems tool window</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.jetbrains.IntelliJ-IDEA-Ultimate/refs/heads/master/screenshots/CodeDuplicates.png</image>
            <caption>Detection of code duplicates</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="2025.1.2" date="2025-06-04">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/intellij-idea-2025-1-2/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The IDE no longer fails to start if a plugin defines an action with unresolved message bundle keys, and it now provides a report identifying the problematic plugin.</li>
                    <li>The IDE no longer produces the false positive “Package is declared in module which is not in the module graph” warning.</li>
                    <li>The IDE once again correctly takes compilerArgs from pom.xml into account when building Maven projects.</li>
                    <li>The GitLab code review mode now functions as expected, correctly displaying changes with proper highlighting.</li>
                    <li>Working directories are once again preserved upon restart when working with the new terminal.</li>
                    <li>Inspections in Terraform can now be suppressed again.</li>
                    <li>Font size rescaling for the Quick Documentation popup works as expected.</li>
                    <li>The Git option now appears correctly in the context menu when right-clicking a file or folder in a project located on a path that includes a symbolic link.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.1.1.1" date="2025-05-09">
            <url type="details">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/articles/IDEA-A-2100662430/IntelliJ-IDEA-2025.1.1.1-251.25410.129-build-Release-Notes</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>FIXED: Android plugin breaks Kotlin functionality in release 2025.1.1 after update from 2025.1</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.1.1" date="2025-05-07">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/intellij-idea-2025-1-1/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Setting backup and synchronization via Backup and Sync now works as expected upon authorization with JetBrains Account.</li>
                    <li>Debugging tests when using Gradle 7.x.x no longer fails.</li>
                    <li>The IDE again correctly imports Maven projects that use several –add-exports arguments.</li>
                    <li>The Paths filter in the Git tool window again works as expected, filtering branches according to the selected repository.</li>
                    <li>Zsh with custom config files again works correctly in the IDE terminal.</li>
                    <li>It is again possible to deploy applications to WildFly from the IDE when using Java 24.</li>
                    <li>The Markdown preview is now consistently displayed.</li>
                    <li>Text copied from tooltip popups via Option/Alt + click no longer includes unwanted HTML tags.</li>
                    <li>The Kotest tool window is again consistently available and works as expected.</li>
                    <li>It is now possible to disable the HTTP Client to encode special characters like +, @, %, and more in URLs so they are sent as is by adding the @no-auto-encoding annotation before the request.</li>
                    <li>The IDE now correctly respects @Nullable on local variables when a default qualifier is used.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2025.1" date="2025-04-16">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Full support for all features in the Java 24 release, ensuring a seamless experience with the newest language updates.</li>
                    <li>K2 mode is enabled by default, marking a major milestone in our journey to enhance code analysis, memory efficiency, and overall performance for Kotlin development in IntelliJ IDEA. Active users are already experiencing a smoother workflow, and we’re continuing to address outstanding issues, refine refactorings and inspections, and further improve quality based on your feedback.</li>
                    <li>You can now pause and resume watch evaluations during debugging to control the potential side effects of watch computations.</li>
                    <li>Kotlin Notebook, a new interactive environment for JVM developers, is now a built-in feature of IntelliJ IDEA! Kotlin notebooks are perfect for a wide range of tasks – from real-time prototyping, presenting, log parsing, and documentation writing to in-depth data analysis and visualization.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2024.3.5" date="2025-03-18">
            <url type="details">https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2024-3-5/</url>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>The code completion popup once again includes a dropdown menu, allowing for quick access to additional actions and settings.</li>
                    <li>You can now customize the hostname length in HostLabelDropdown, improving usability for infrastructures with longer hostnames.</li>
                    <li>Breakpoints in Dart code can once again be set and hit.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
</component>
